<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Operating System Fundamentals">
  
	<intro>
		<esrtitle>General Purpose Operating System</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>NIAP and CESG</maintainer>
		<identifier>42</identifier>
		<version>0.8</version>
		<status>draft</status>
		<issuedate>19 March 2015</issuedate>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
		This section sets the context for not only the ESR, but what is 
		expected of the resulting Protection Profile (PP). The intent is 
		that the remaining sections provide succinct statements that 
		highlight the relevant aspects to be addressed by the Technical 
		Community (TC) constructing the PP. Here, the authors provide a 
		narrative that introduces the reader to the problem being solved, 
		and presents key aspects that support or guide the TC, and may
		elaborate on subtleties not apparent in the “bulleted” high level
		statements.
	</section>
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
	  This section is intended to provide the initial scope/bound of the 
	  security problem by providing the reader with concise statements 
	  regarding the scenarios in which the technology is being used. The 
	  intended usage presented here should lay the groundwork for the 
	  identifying the resources to be protected, and what threats must be
	  considered in the drafting of the Essential Security Requirements 
	  (ESR) and for the TC to consider when writing the PP.
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
    	  This section is intended to provide the initial scope/bound of the 
    	  security problem by providing the reader with concise statements
    	  regarding the scenarios in which the technology is being used. The 
    	  intended usage presented here should lay the groundwork for the 
    	  identifying the resources to be protected, and what threats must be
    	  considered in the drafting of the Essential Security Requirements 
    	  (ESR) and for the TC to consider when writing the PP.
	</section>

	<section title="Attacker access" id="attackeraccess"> 
	  The following assumptions are made about
	  attackers' ability to develop attacks: 
	  <ul>
	    <li> An attacker has an arbitrary amount of time to analyze the behavior of the product, its
	    interaction with its platform, and the data it transmits over the network. </li>
	    <li> An attacker is able to acquire their own copy of the target product and study its
	    behavior on a platform that they control. </li>
	  </ul>
	  <p/> The attacker is expected to engage in the following general classes of attack: <!-- added in order to allow for rather direct flow to Threats section in PP -->
	  <ul>
	    <li> Network eavesdropping, in which an attacker may monitor and gain access to data
	    exchanged between the product and other endpoints. </li>
	    <li> Network attack, in which an attacker may initiate malicious communications with the
	    product or alter communications between the product and other endpoints. </li>
	    <li> Local attack, in which an attacker has gained the ability to execute code on the
	    system, which may be used to escalate privilege or access data without
	    authorization. </li>
	    <li> Limited physical access attack, in which an attacker may attempt to access data on
	    the system by virtue of being physically present for a limited period of time. This
	    limited physical access does not include attacks in which the attacker could
	    disassemble the system to gain access to its storage media or manipulate the product's
	    underlying hardware and firmware. Systems used for working remotely, such as laptops
	    and tablets, for which an attacker could gain longer physical access to, should
	    apply additional protections that are provided by products evaluated against other
	    Protection Profiles (e.g. FDE cPP). </li>
	    <li> Persistence, in which an attacker has already exploited the system and wishes to
	    maintain presence on the system. </li>
	  </ul>
	</section>
	
	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
        	This is where the authors present an initial set of English 
        	requirements that specify security functionality, rather than 
        	design and/or implementation characteristics. These requirements 
        	will provide the foundation for which the detailed set of 
        	requirements is derived. It is important that the requirements 
        	captured here make an attempt to fully address the categories 
        	(e.g., access control, identification and authentication, 
        	management capabilities, roles of administration, secure 
        	communications, and audit). That's not to say the requirements are 
        	fully specified or detailed enough to simply translate to Common 
        	Criteria security functional requirements. The goal is that there 
        	is enough information contained here, as well as the other sections
        	of this document, to provide the TC enough information to ensure 
        	they have an understanding of what is minimally required in breath.
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
	  Simply put, this section presents the aspects of the product and 
	  its	intended environment that can be assumed to hold true. This 
	  will provide additional scope on the resulting PP.

	  The following assumptions are made for the operating system product and its operational
	  environment: <ul>
			<li>The underlying platform is physically protected, to a large extent. The hardware
				that the product manages is secured by defensive measures that make physical attacks
				impractical for most attackers. At the same time, casual passersby might attempt to
				trivially access the system. </li>
			<li>The product implements some security-relevant functionality that does not require
				evaluation (e.g., network time synchronization, process scheduling, and virtual
				memory management including process separation). </li>
			<li>Depending on configuration and capability, the product may or may not be: <ul>
					<li>configuration-managed by the enterprise</li>
					<li>bound to directory services to support multi-user login</li> </ul>
			</li>
			<li> The product runs application software developed by a third-party. The applications are
				not intentionally developed to be malicious, but can contain inadvertent coding
				errors. These errors introduce risk that control of an application may be seized by
				a malicious entity. The product shall confine these applications within the originally
				designated operating environment. </li>
			<li>The platform is connected to a network. For purposes of sending/receiving data, to
				include software updates, the platform is connected to other entities. Other
				entities on the network are not inherently trustable. </li>
			<li>Administrators are not malicious in nature.</li>
			<li> Users are not malicious in nature, though they may inadvertently or intentionally engage in risky behavior. </li>
		</ul>
	</section>


	<section title="Optional Extensions" id="extensions"> 
		Additional security functionality that may
		be appropriate for some use cases, and can be expressed in extensions to this document,
		includes: 
		<ul>
			<li></li>
		</ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Outside the TOE's Scope" id="outsidescope">
	  <!--
			This is where the authors explicitly state things they do not want 
			to be considered for inclusion in an evaluation against a 
			resulting PP.  Items expressed here could include threats, 
			functions or capabilities that would require assurance activities 
			that are too subjective, or specific expertise not available in the
			evaluation facilities expected to assess products against the PP 
	  -->
		The following list contains items that are explicitly out-of-scope for any evaluation
		against the product PP <ul>
			<li>Malicious, Highly-Privileged Administrators - Highly-privileged administrators
				acting maliciously can disable most, if not all, security protections on the product.
				Additionally procedural controls that are out of scope of this document should be
				considered to help highlight administrator accounts acting suspiciously.</li>
			<li>Zero Days - The disclosure of recently published vulnerabilities (Zero Days) should
				not be used as a reason to fail an product undergoing evaluation.</li>
			<li>Unofficial Versions - Non-vendor supplied install images often contain added
				functionality and may weaken the normal operating functionality of the product</li>
			<li>Platform - The product PP shall not address the hardware or firmware of its underlying
				platform to include the boot sequence before control is handed off to the product. That
				the platform itself is virtual or physical is irrelevant to any evaluations. </li>
			<li>Applications - The product PP shall not address applications that are not delivered as
				part of the product installation process. </li>
		</ul>
	</section>
</ESR>
