<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Mobile Device Fundamentals">
  
	<intro>
		<esrtitle>Protection Profile for Mobile Devices: Mobile Security Foundation</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>Information Assurance Directorate</maintainer>
		<identifier>001</identifier>
		<version>0.02</version>
		<status>Draft</status>
		<issuedate/>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
		This assurance standard specifies information security requirements for Mobile Devices for 
		use in an enterprise. A Mobile Device in the context of this assurance standard is a device 
		which is composed of a hardware platform and its system software. The device typically 
		provides wireless connectivity and uses application software for functions like secure 
		messaging, email, web, VPN connection, and VoIP (Voice over IP), for access to the 
		protected enterprise network, enterprise data and applications, and for communicating to 
		other mobile devices.
	<br/>
		Examples of a “mobile device” that should claim compliance to this assurance standard 
		include smartphones, tablet computers, and other mobile devices with similar capabilities.
	<br/>
		The Mobile Device provides essential services, such as cryptographic services, data-at-rest 
		protection, and key storage services to support the secure operation of applications on the 
		device.  Additional security features such as security policy enforcement, application 
		mandatory access control, anti-exploitation features, user authentication, and software integrity 
		protection are implemented in order to address threats.
	<br/>
		This assurance standard describes these essential security services provided by the Mobile 
		Device and serving as a foundation for a secure mobile architecture. It is expected that a 
		typical deployment would also include either third-party or bundled components that 
		provide:
		<ul>
			<li>Data in transit protection (e.g. VPN Clientm VoIP Client, Web Browser)</li>
			<li>Security policy management (e.g. MDM System)</li>
		</ul>
	<br/>
		If these components are bundled as part of the Mobile Device by the manufacturer, they 
		may be separately validated against the related assurance standards. Additional 
		applications that may come pre-installed on the Mobile Device that are not validated are 
		considered to be potentially flawed, but not malicious.  Examples include VoIP client, email 
		client, and web browser.
	<br/>
		<b>Related assurance standards</b>
		This assurance standard is one of a set of complementary 
		Mobility assurance standards that can be layered together to 
		provide a full deployment.  The set of assurance standards will 
		consist of:
		<ol>
			<li>Mobile Device: Mobile Security Foundations</li>
			<li>Mobile Device Management</li>
			<li>VPN Client &amp; Gateway</li>
			<li>VoIP Client &amp; SIP Server</li>
			<li>Email Client</li>
			<li>Web Browser</li>
		</ol>
	</section>
	
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
	  	A selection of use cases is elaborated below.
	<br/>
		<b>[USE CASE 1] Enterprise-furnished device for general-purpose enterprise use and limited 
			personal use</b>
		An enterprise-furnished device for general-purpose business use entails a significant degree 
		of enterprise control over configuration and, possibly, software inventory. The enterprise 
		elects to provide users with mobile devices and additional applications (such as VPN or 
		email clients) in order to maintain control of their sensitive data and security of their 
		networks, while trying to balance the constraints of usability and security and 
		considerations of personal ownership and control. Users may use Internet connectivity to 
		browse the web or access corporate mail or run enterprise applications, but this 
		connectivity may be under significant control of the enterprise.
	<br/>
		<b>[USE CASE 2]Enterprise-furnished device for specialized, high-security use</b>
		An enterprise-furnished device with intentionally-limited network connectivity, tightly-
		controlled configuration, and limited software inventory is appropriate for specialized, high-
		security use cases. For example, the device may not be permitted connectivity to any 
		external peripherals. It may only be able to communicate via its WiFi or cellular radios with 
		the enterprise-run network, which may not even permit connectivity to the Internet. Use of 
		the device may entail compliance with policies that would not be considered realistic in any 
		general-purpose use case, yet may mitigate risks to highly sensitive information. As in the 
		previous case, the enterprise will look for additional applications providing enterprise 
		connectivity and services to have a similar level of assurance as the platform.
	<br/>
		<b>[USE CASE 3] Personally-furnished device for personal and enterprise use</b>
		A personally-furnished device which is used for both personal activities and enterprise data 
		is commonly called Bring Your Own Device (BYOD). Unlike in the enterprise-furnished cases, 
		in this use case the enterprise is limited in what security policies it can enforce on the device 
		because the user purchased the device for personal use and is unlikely to accept 
		policies that limit the functionality of the device. However, because the enterprise allows 
		the user full (or nearly full) access to the enterprise network, the enterprise will require 
		certain security policies, for example a password or screenlock policy, and may require 
		assured enterprise software, for example a VPN client, before allowing access.
	<br/>
		<b>[USE CASE 4] Personally-furnished device for personal and limited enterprise use</b>
		A personally-furnished device may also be given access to limited enterprise services such as 
		enterprise email. Because the user does not have full access to the enterprise or enterprise 
		data, the enterprise may not need to enforce any security policies on the device. However, 
		the enterprise may want secure email and web browsing with assurance that the services 
		being provided to those clients by the mobile device are not compromised.
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
    	High-level resources to be protected are identified in the Background/Purpose.
	</section>

	<section title="Attacker access" id="attackeraccess"> 
	    Mobile devices are subject to the threats of traditional computer systems along with those 
	    entailed by their mobile nature. The requirements in this assurance standard were 
	    developed to address the threats of network eavesdropping, network attacks, physical 
	    access, and non-malicious (but potentially flawed) apps.
	<br/>
		<ul>
			<li>Network eavesdropping involves an attack positioned on a wireless 
				communications channel or elsewhere on the network infrastructure. Attackers may 
				monitor and gain access to data exchanged between the Mobile Device and other 
				endpoints.</li>
		<br/>
			<li>Network attacks encompass situations in which an attacker is positioned on a 
				wireless communications channel or elsewhere on the network 
				infrastructure. Attackers may initiate communications with the Mobile Device or 
				alter communications between the Mobile Device and other endpoints in order to 
				compromise the Mobile Device. These attacks include malicious software updates 
				of any apps or system software on the device. These attacks include spoofing of 
				endpoint devices, such as MDM or VPN servers. These attacks also include malicious 
				web pages or email attachments which are usually delivered over the network to 
				devices.</li>
		<br/>
			<li>Physical access threats involve loss or theft of the Mobile Device which may give rise 
				to lose of confidentiality of user data including credentials. These may involve 
				attacks which attempt to access the device through external hardware ports, 
				through its user interface, and also through direct and possibly destructive access to 
				its storage media. The goal of such attacks is to access data from a lost or stolen 
				device which is not expected to return to its user. Defending against device re-use 
				after physical compromise is out of scope for this assurance standard.</li>
		<br/>
			<li>Malicious or flawed app threats exist because apps loaded onto the Mobile Device 
				may include malicious or exploitable code. This code could be included intentionally 
				by its developer or unknowingly by the developer, perhaps as a software 
				library. Malicious apps may attempt to exfiltrate data to which they have 
				access. They may also conduct attacks against the platform's system software which 
				will provide them with additional privileges and the ability to conduct further 
				malicious activities. Malicious apps may be able to control the device's sensors (GPS, 
				camera, microphone) to gather intelligence about the user's surroundings even 
				when those activities do not involve data resident or transmitted from the device. 
				Flawed apps may give an attack access to perform network-based or physical 
				attacks that otherwise would have been prevented.</li>
		<br/>
			<li>Persistent access to a device by an attacker implies that the device has lost integrity 
				and cannot regain it. The device has likely lost this integrity due to some other 
				threat vector, yet the continued access by an attacker constitutes an ongoing threat 
				in itself. In this case the device and its data may be controlled by an adversary at 
				least as well as by its legitimate owner.</li>
		</ul>
	</section>
	
	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
        
        Random Bit Generation
		<ul>
			<li>RBG1: The MD shall perform all deterministic random bit generation services in 
				accordance with [selection, choose one of: NIST Special Publication 80090
				using [selection: Hash_DRBG (any), HMAC_DRBG (any),
				CTR_DRBG (AES), Dual_EC_DRBG (any)]; FIPS Pub 1402
				Annex C: X9.31 Appendix 2.4 using AES].
			</li>
			<li>RBG2: The deterministic RBG (RBG1)
				shall be seeded with a minimum of [selection, choose one of: 128
				bits, 256 bits] of entropy at least equal to the greatest security strength
				(according to NIST SP80057) of the
				keys and authorization factors that it will generate. The deterministic RBG shall be seeded by an entropy
				source that accumulated entropy from from an MD hardwarebased noise source, and [selection: a
				softwarebased noise source, other independent MDhardwarebased
				noise source, no other noise source].
			</li>
		</ul>
        
		<br/>
		
		Keys
		<ul>
			<li>KEY1: The MD shall support a hardwareprotected
				REK with an AES key size of 128 or 256 bits. The key
				shall not be able to be imported to or exported from the hardware. System software on the MD shall be able
				only to request encryption/decryption by the key. A REK shall be generated by a RBG in accordance with
				RBG1 and RBG2.
			</li>
		</ul>
		
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
	  <ol>
	  	<li>The Mobile Device will be provisioned for a specific mobile user in the enterprise 
	  		environment by the administrator prior to use by the mobile user.</li>
	  	<br/>
	  	<li>The administrator will configure the Mobile Device security functions correctly to 
	  		create the intended security policy.</li>
	  	<br/>
	  	<li>The Mobile User will immediately notify the administrator if the Mobile Device is 
	  		lost or stolen.</li>
	  	<br/>
	  	<li>The Mobile User is not malicious, and exercises precautions to reduce the risk of 
	  		loss or theft of the Mobile Device.</li>
	  	<br/>
	  </ol>
	</section>

	<section title="Optional Extensions" id="extensions"> 
		Optional Extensions are Identified within the Security Requirements.
	</section>

	<section title="Outside the TOE's Scope" id="outsidescope">
	  	The Mobile Device is also vulnerable due to the access of service providers who, in their role, 
	  	can easily eavesdrop on mobile communications or inject malicious or flawed code into the 
	  	mobile device. At this time, this assurance standard provides few mitigations to the access 
	  	available to service providers, or adversaries posing as service providers; however, several 
	  	future requirements addressing this threat are identified, with the expectation that industry 
	  	will feedback as to the feasibility of such requirements.
	</section>
</ESR>
