<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="General Purpose Operating System"
    xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <!-- <inline-comment color='green'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <!-- <inline-comment color='blue' linebreak='yes'> Hello World QQQQ </inline-comment> -->
  <PPReference title="PP Reference">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Protection Profile for QQQQ</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>4.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2015-08-14</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1R4</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>QQQQ</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>Round 1</version>
      <date>2015-04-23</date>
      <subject>First draft of version 4.0 for comment</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>4.0</version>
      <date>2015-08-14</date>
      <subject>Release - significant revision</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview"> The scope of this Protection Profile (PP) is to
      describe the security functionality of operating systems in terms of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>
      and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products.
      An operating system is software that manages computer hardware and software
      resources, and provides common services for application programs. The hardware
      it manages may be physical or virtual.
    </section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary"> The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
      technology terms used in this Protection Profile. <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms"
        id="ccterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description>
	      The product under evaluation. In this case, the Operating System as described in section 
	      <xref linkend="TOEboundary"/> and its
              supporting documentation.
	    </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a <abbr
                linkend="ST"/>. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Technology Terms" id="techterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="SOMETHING"></abbr></term>
            <description>
	    </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
	  </section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      <subsection title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary">
        <figure entity="images/Toe.png" title="Figure 1: General TOE " id="toe"/>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="TOE Platform" id="TOEplatform">
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">Requirements in this Protection Profile are designed to
      address the security problems in at least the following use cases. These use cases are intentionally
      very broad, as many specific use cases exist for an operating system. These use cases may also
      overlap with one another.  An operating system's functionality may even be effectively extended by
      privileged applications installed onto it.  However, these are out of scope of this PP. <usecases>
        <usecase title="End User Devices" id="enduserdevices">
          <description>
          </description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="ccl">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description> To be conformant to this PP, a <abbr linkend="ST"/> must demonstrate Exact
          Conformance, a subset of Strict Conformance as defined in <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1
          (ASE_CCL). The <abbr linkend="ST"/> must include all components in this PP that are: <h:ul>
            <h:li>unconditional (which are always required)</h:li>
            <h:li>selection-based (which are required when certain <h:i>selections</h:i> are chosen in the
              unconditional requirements)</h:li>
          </h:ul>and may include components that are <h:ul>
            <h:li>optional or</h:li>
            <h:li>objective.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          <InsertAppendixExplainer/> The <abbr linkend="ST"/> may iterate any of these components,
          but it must not include any additional component (e.g. from CC Part 2 or 3 or a PP not
          conformant with this one, or extended by the <abbr linkend="ST"/>) not defined in this PP
          or a PP conformant to this one. 
          <h:br/>
		  Some components in this Protection Profile have a dependency on
		  other components.  In accordance with <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1, <appref linkend="satisfiedreqs"/> 
          includes justifications for those cases where the PP does not explicitly contain the component
		  upon which there is a dependency.
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This PP is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (extended) of Common Criteria
          Version 3.1, Revision 4.<cite linkend="bibCC"/>.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="PP Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any other Protection
          Profile.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="Package Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any packages.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Problem Definition" id="spd">The security problem is described in terms
    of the threats that the <abbr linkend="OS"/> is expected to address, assumptions about the
    operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the <abbr linkend="OS"/>
    is expected to enforce. <section title="Threats" id="threats">
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.QQQQ">
          <description> </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.QQQQ">
            <rationale>The threat T.QQQQ is countered by O.QQQQ as this
              provides for .</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>
    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.QQQQ">
          <description> The product relies QQQQ its execution. This underlying platform is out of scope of this PP. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.PLATFORM">
            <rationale> The operational environment objective OE.PLATFORM is realized through
              A.PLATFORM. </rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
<!--    <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="OSPs">
      <OSPs>
        <OSP id="P.ENTERPRISE">
          <description>If the OS is bound to a directory or management server, the configuration of
            the OS software must be capable of adhering to the enterprise security policies
            distributed by them.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
            <rationale>The organizational security policy P.ENTERPRISE is enforced through the
              objective O.MANAGEMENT as this objective represents how the enterprise and user assert
              management over the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </OSP>
      </OSPs>
    </section> -->
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.ACCOUNTABILITY">
          <description> Conformant <abbr linkend="OS"/>s ensure that information exists that allows
            administrators to discover unintentional issues with the configuration and operation of
            the operating system and discover its cause.  Gathering event information and immediately 
            transmitting it to another system can also enable incident response in the event
            of system compromise.</description>
          <component-refer ref="fau_gen.1"/>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment"
      id="SecurityObjectivesTOEorEnvironment">The following security objectives for the operational
      environment assist the <abbr linkend="OS"/> in correctly providing its security functionality.
      These track with the assumptions about the environment. <SOEs>
        <SOE id="OE.PLATFORM">
          <description>The <abbr linkend="OS"/> relies on being installed on trusted
            hardware.</description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PROPER_USER">
          <description> The user of the <abbr linkend="OS"/> is not willfully negligent or hostile,
            and uses the software within compliance of the applied enterprise security policy.
            Standard user accounts are provisioned in accordance with the least privilege model.
            Users requiring higher levels of access should have a separate account dedicated for
            that use. </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PROPER_ADMIN">
          <description> The administrator of the <abbr linkend="OS"/> is not careless, willfully
            negligent or hostile, and administers the OS within compliance of the applied enterprise
            security policy. </description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs></section>
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR">This section describes how the
      assumptions, threats, and organizational security policies map to the security objectives.
      <InsertSPDCorrespondence/></section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the <abbr linkend="OS"/>. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 and assurance components from Part 3 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The
    following notations are used: <h:ul>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Refinement</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:b>bold text</h:b>): is used to add details to a
        requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Selection</h:b> (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Assignment</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the
        value in square brackets indicates assignment.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Iteration</h:b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
        "(1)")</h:li>
    </h:ul>
    <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFRs">The Security Functional Requirements
      included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
      components. 
      <subsection title="QQQQ" id="QQQQ">
        <f-component id="QQQ_QQQ.1" name="QQQQQ" status="threshold">
          <f-element id="QQQ_QQQ.1.1">
            <title> 
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>
	    </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Assurance Requirements" id="SARs">
      The Security Objectives in 
      <secref linkend="obj"/> were constructed to address threats identified in
      <secref linkend="threats"/>. The Security Functional Requirements (<abbr linkend="SFR"/>s)
      in <secref linkend="SFRs"/> are a formal instantiation of the Security Objectives. The PP
      identifies the Security Assurance Requirements (<abbr linkend="SAR"/>s) to frame the extent to
      which the evaluator assesses the documentation applicable for the evaluation and performs
      independent testing. <h:br/> This section lists the set of <abbr linkend="SAR"/>s from CC part 3
      that are required in evaluations against this PP. Individual Assurance Activities
      <!--(AAs). Never use these again --> to be performed are specified both in <secref
        linkend="req"/> as well as in this section. <h:br/> The general model for evaluation of <abbr
        linkend="OS"/>s against STs written to conform to this PP is as follows: <h:br/> After the
        <abbr linkend="ST"/> has been approved for evaluation, the <abbr class="expanded"
        title="Information Technology Security Evaluation Facility">ITSEF</abbr> will obtain the
        <abbr linkend="OS"/>, supporting environmental IT, and the administrative/user guides for
      the OS. The ITSEF is expected to perform actions mandated by the Common Evaluation
      Methodology (CEM) for the ASE and ALC SARs. The ITSEF also performs the Assurance Activities
      contained within <secref linkend="req"/>, which are intended to be an interpretation of the
      other CEM assurance requirements as they apply to the specific technology instantiated in the
      OS. The Assurance Activities that are captured in <secref linkend="req"/> also provide
      clarification as to what the developer needs to provide to demonstrate the OS is compliant
      with the PP. <subsection title="Class ASE: Security Target" id="ase">As per ASE activities
        defined in <cite linkend="bibCEM"/>.</subsection>
      <subsection title="Class ADV: Development" id="adv">The information about the <abbr
          linkend="OS"/> is contained in the guidance documentation available to the end user as
        well as the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> portion of the <abbr linkend="ST"/>. The <abbr
          linkend="OS"/> developer must concur with the description of the product that is
        contained in the TSS as it relates to the functional requirements. The Assurance Activities
        contained in <secref linkend="SFRs"/> should provide the <abbr linkend="ST"/> authors with
        sufficient information to determine the appropriate content for the TSS section.
          <a-component id="adv_fsp.1" name="Basic Functional Specification (ADV_FSP.1)">The
          functional specification describes the <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>s. It is not
          necessary to have a formal or complete specification of these interfaces. Additionally,
          because <abbr linkend="OS"/>s conforming to this PP will necessarily have interfaces to
          the Operational Environment that are not directly invokable by <abbr linkend="OS"/>
          users, there is little point specifying that such interfaces be described in and of
          themselves since only indirect testing of such interfaces may be possible. For this PP,
          the activities for this family should focus on understanding the interfaces presented in
          the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> in response to the functional requirements and the interfaces
          presented in the AGD documentation. No additional “functional specification” documentation
          is necessary to satisfy the assurance activities specified. The interfaces that need to be
          evaluated are characterized through the information needed to perform the assurance
          activities listed, rather than as an independent, abstract list. 
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1D">
              <title>The developer shall provide a functional specification.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2D">
              <title>The developer shall provide a tracing from the functional specification to the
              SFRs.</title>
              <note role="application">As indicated in the introduction to this section, the
              functional specification is comprised of the information contained in the AGD_OPE and
              AGD_PRE documentation. The developer may reference a website accessible to application
              developers and the evaluator. The assurance activities in the functional requirements
              point to evidence that should exist in the documentation and <abbr linkend="TSS"/>
              section; since these are directly associated with the SFRs, the tracing in element
              ADV_FSP.1.2D is implicitly already done and no additional documentation is
              necessary.</note>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1C">
              <title>The functional specification shall describe the purpose and method of use for
              each SFR-enforcing and SFR-supporting <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2C">
              <title>The functional specification shall identify all parameters associated with each
              SFR-enforcing and SFR-supporting <abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.3C">
              <title>The functional specification shall provide rationale for the implicit
              categorization of interfaces as SFR-non-interfering.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.4C">
              <title>
		The tracing shall demonstrate that the SFRs trace to 
		<abbr title="TSF Interface">TSFI</abbr>s 
		in the functional specification.
	      </title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.1E">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ADV_FSP.1.2E">
              <title>The evaluator shall determine that the functional specification is an accurate
              and complete instantiation of the SFRs.</title>
              <aactivity>There are no specific assurance activities associated with these SARs, except
              ensuring the information is provided. The functional specification documentation is
              provided to support the evaluation activities described in <secref linkend="SFRs"/>, and
              other activities described for AGD, ATE, and AVA SARs. The requirements on the content
              of the functional specification information is implicitly assessed by virtue of the
              other assurance activities being performed; if the evaluator is unable to perform an
              activity because there is insufficient interface information, then an adequate
              functional specification has not been provided.
	      </aactivity>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="agd" title="Class AGD: Guidance Documentation">The guidance documents will be
        provided with the <abbr linkend="ST"/>. Guidance must include a description of how the IT
        personnel verifies that the Operational Environment can fulfill its role for the security
        functionality. The documentation should be in an informal style and readable by the IT
        personnel. Guidance must be provided for every operational environment that the product
        supports as claimed in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>. This guidance includes instructions to
        successfully install the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> in that environment; and Instructions to
        manage the security of the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> as a product and as a component of the
        larger operational environment. Guidance pertaining to particular security functionality is
        also provided; requirements on such guidance are contained in the assurance activities
        specified with each requirement. 
	<a-component id="agd_ope.1" name="Operational User Guidance (AGD_OPE.1)">
	  <group type="dev-action">
	    <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1D">
	      <title>The developer shall provide operational user guidance.</title>
	      <note role="application">The operational user guidance does not have to be contained in a
	      single document. Guidance to users, administrators and application developers can be
              spread among documents or web pages. 
	      Rather than repeat information here, the developer should
              review the assurance activities for this component to ascertain the specifics of the
              guidance that the evaluator will be checking for. This will provide the necessary
              information for the preparation of acceptable guidance.</note>
            </a-element>
          </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role, the
              user-accessible functions and privileges that should be controlled in a secure
              processing environment, including appropriate warnings.</title>
              <note role="application">User and administrator are to be considered in the definition
              of user role.</note>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.2C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role, how to use the
              available interfaces provided by the <abbr linkend="OS"/> in a secure manner.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.3C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall describe, for each user role, the available
              functions and interfaces, in particular all security parameters under the control of
              the user, indicating secure values as appropriate.</title>
              <note role="application">
		This portion of the operational user guidance should be presented
		in the form of a checklist that can be quickly executed by IT personnel (or end-users, 
		when necessary) and suitable for use in compliance activities.
		When possible, this guidance is to be expressed in the eXtensible Configuration 
		Checklist Description Format (XCCDF) to
		support security automation.  
		Minimally, it should be presented in a structured 
		format which includes a title for each configuration item, 
		instructions for achieving the secure configuration, and any relevant rationale.  
              </note>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.4C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall, for each user role, clearly present each
              type of security-relevant event relative to the user-accessible functions that need to
              be performed, including changing the security characteristics of entities under the
              control of the <abbr linkend="TSF"/>.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.5C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall identify all possible modes of operation of
              the <abbr linkend="OS"/> (including operation following failure or operational
              error), their consequences, and implications for maintaining secure operation.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.6C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall, for each user role, describe the security
              measures to be followed in order to fulfill the security objectives for the
              operational environment as described in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.7C">
              <title>The operational user guidance shall be clear and reasonable.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="AGD_OPE.1.1E">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence. </title>
              <aactivity>Some of the contents of the operational guidance are verified by the
              assurance activities in <secref linkend="SFRs"/> and evaluation of the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/> according to the <cite linkend="bibCEM"/>. The following additional
              information is also required. If cryptographic functions are provided by the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/>, the operational guidance shall contain instructions for configuring
              the cryptographic engine associated with the evaluated configuration of the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/>. It shall provide a warning to the administrator that use of other
              cryptographic engines was not evaluated nor tested during the CC evaluation of the
              <abbr linkend="OS"/>. The documentation must describe the process for verifying
              updates to the <abbr linkend="OS"/> by verifying a digital signature – this may be
              done by the <abbr linkend="OS"/> or the underlying platform. The evaluator will
              verify that this process includes the following steps: Instructions for obtaining the
              update itself. This should include instructions for making the update accessible to
              the <abbr linkend="OS"/> (e.g., placement in a specific directory). Instructions for
              initiating the update process, as well as discerning whether the process was
              successful or unsuccessful. This includes generation of the hash/digital signature.
              The <abbr linkend="OS"/> will likely contain security functionality that does not
              fall in the scope of evaluation under this PP. The operational guidance shall make it
              clear to an administrator which security functionality is covered by the evaluation
              activities. </aactivity>
          </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
        <a-component id="agd_pre.1" name="Preparative Procedures (AGD_PRE.1)">
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1D">
              <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="OS"/>, including its preparative
              procedures.</title>
              <note role="application">As with the operational guidance, the developer should look to
              the assurance activities to determine the required content with respect to preparative
              procedures.</note>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1C">
              <title>The preparative procedures shall describe all the steps necessary for secure
              acceptance of the delivered <abbr linkend="OS"/> in accordance with the developer's
              delivery procedures.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.2C">
              <title>The preparative procedures shall describe all the steps necessary for secure
              installation of the <abbr linkend="OS"/> and for the secure preparation of the
              operational environment in accordance with the security objectives for the operational
              environment as described in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.1E">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="AGD_PRE.1.2E">
              <title>The evaluator shall apply the preparative procedures to confirm that the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/> can be prepared securely for operation.</title>
              <aactivity>As indicated in the introduction above, there are significant expectations
              with respect to the documentation—especially when configuring the operational
              environment to support <abbr linkend="OS"/> functional requirements. The evaluator
              shall check to ensure that the guidance provided for the <abbr linkend="OS"/>
              adequately addresses all platforms claimed for the <abbr linkend="OS"/> in the <abbr
              linkend="ST"/>. </aactivity>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="alc" title="Class ALC: Life-cycle Support"> At the assurance level provided
        for OSs conformant to this PP, life-cycle support is limited to end-user-visible aspects of
        the life-cycle, rather than an examination of the OS vendor’s development and configuration
        management process. This is not meant to diminish the critical role that a developer’s
        practices play in contributing to the overall trustworthiness of a product; rather, it is a
        reflection on the information to be made available for evaluation at this assurance level.
          <a-component id="alc_cmc.1" name="Labeling of the TOE (ALC_CMC.1)">This component is
          targeted at identifying the <abbr linkend="OS"/> such that it can be distinguished from
          other products or versions from the same vendor and can be easily specified when being
          procured by an end user. 
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1d">
              <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="OS"/> and a reference for the
              <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1c">
              <title>The <abbr linkend="OS"/> shall be labeled with a unique reference.</title>
              <note role="application">Unique reference information includes: 
	      <h:ul>
		<h:li>OS Name</h:li>
		<h:li>OS Version</h:li>
		<h:li>OS Description</h:li>
		<h:li>Software Identification (SWID) tags, if available</h:li>
              </h:ul>
              </note>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="alc_cmc.1.1e">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
              <aactivity>The evaluator will check the <abbr linkend="ST"/> to ensure that it contains
              an identifier (such as a product name/version number) that specifically identifies the
              version that meets the requirements of the <abbr linkend="ST"/>. Further, the
              evaluator will check the AGD guidance and <abbr linkend="OS"/> samples received for
              testing to ensure that the version number is consistent with that in the <abbr
              linkend="ST"/>. If the vendor maintains a web site advertising the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/>, the evaluator will examine the information on the web site to
              ensure that the information in the <abbr linkend="ST"/> is sufficient to distinguish
              the product.</aactivity>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
        <a-component id="alc_cms.1" name="TOE CM Coverage (ALC_CMS.1)">
	  Given the scope of the <abbr linkend="OS"/> and its associated evaluation 
	  evidence requirements, this component’s assurance activities are covered 
	  by the assurance activities listed for ALC_CMC.1.
          <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1d">
              <title>
		The developer shall provide a configuration list for the  <abbr linkend="OS"/>.
	      </title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1c">
              <title>The configuration list shall include the following: the <abbr linkend="OS"/>
              itself; and the evaluation evidence required by the SARs.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="alc_cms.1.2c">
              <title>The configuration list shall uniquely identify the configuration items.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
          <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="alc_cms.1.1e">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
              <aactivity>The "evaluation evidence required by the SARs" in this PP is limited to the
              information in the <abbr linkend="ST"/> coupled with the guidance provided to
              administrators and users under the AGD requirements. By ensuring that the <abbr
              linkend="OS"/> is specifically identified and that this identification is
              consistent in the <abbr linkend="ST"/> and in the AGD guidance (as done in the
              assurance activity for ALC_CMC.1), the evaluator implicitly confirms the information
              required by this component. Life-cycle support is targeted aspects of the developer’s
              life-cycle and instructions to providers of applications for the developer’s devices,
              rather than an in-depth examination of the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> manufacturer’s
              development and configuration management process. This is not meant to diminish the
              critical role that a developer’s practices play in contributing to the overall
              trustworthiness of a product; rather, it’s a reflection on the information to be made
              available for evaluation. <h:br/> The evaluator will ensure that the developer has
              identified (in guidance documentation for application developers concerning the
              targeted platform) one or more development environments appropriate for use in
              developing applications for the developer’s platform. For each of these development
              environments, the developer shall provide information on how to configure the
              environment to ensure that buffer overflow protection mechanisms in the environment(s)
              are invoked (e.g., compiler and linker flags). The evaluator will ensure that this documentation
              also includes an indication of whether such protections are on by default, or have to
              be specifically enabled. The evaluator will ensure that the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> is
              uniquely identified (with respect to other products from the <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
              vendor), and that documentation provided by the developer in association with the
              requirements in the <abbr linkend="ST"/> is associated with the <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
              using this unique identification.</aactivity>
          </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
        <a-component id="alc_tsu_ext.1" name="Timely Security Updates"> This component requires the
          OS developer, in conjunction with any other necessary parties, to provide information as
          to how the end-user devices are updated to address security issues in a timely manner. The
          documentation describes the process of providing updates to the public from the time a
          security flaw is reported/discovered, to the time an update is released. This description
          includes the parties involved (e.g., the developer, carriers(s)) and the steps that are
          performed (e.g., developer testing, carrier testing), including worst case time periods,
          before an update is made available to the public. 
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="alc_tsu_ext.1.1d">
              <title>The developer shall provide a description in the TSS of how timely security
              updates are made to the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="alc_tsu_ext.1.2d">
              <title> The developer shall provide a description in the TSS of how users are notified
              when updates change security properties or the configuration of the product. </title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="alc_tsu_ext.1.1c">
              <title>The description shall include the process for creating and deploying security
              updates for the <abbr linkend="OS"/> software.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="alc_tsu_ext.1.2c">
              <title>The description shall include the mechanisms publicly available for reporting
              security issues pertaining to the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</title>
              <note> The reporting mechanism could include web sites, email addresses, as well as a
              means to protect the sensitive nature of the report (e.g., public keys that could be
              used to encrypt the details of a proof-of-concept exploit). </note>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="alc_tsu_ext.1.1e">
              <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all
              requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
              <aactivity> The evaluator will verify that the TSS contains a description of the timely
              security update process used by the developer to create and deploy security updates.
              The evaluator will verify that this description addresses the entire application. The
              evaluator will also verify that, in addition to the OS developer’s process, any
              third-party processes are also addressed in the description. The evaluator will also
              verify that each mechanism for deployment of security updates is described. <h:br/> The
              evaluator will verify that, for each deployment mechanism described for the update
              process, the TSS lists a time between public disclosure of a vulnerability and public
              availability of the security update to the OS patching this vulnerability, to include
              any third-party or carrier delays in deployment. The evaluator will verify that this
              time is expressed in a number or range of days. <h:br/> The evaluator will verify that
              this description includes the publicly available mechanisms (including either an email
              address or website) for reporting security issues related to the OS. The evaluator
              shall verify that the description of this mechanism includes a method for protecting
              the report either using a public key for encrypting email or a trusted channel for a
              website. </aactivity>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ate" title="Class ATE: Tests">Testing is specified for functional aspects of
        the system as well as aspects that take advantage of design or implementation weaknesses.
        The former is done through the ATE_IND family, while the latter is through the AVA_VAN
        family. At the assurance level specified in this PP, testing is based on advertised
        functionality and interfaces with dependency on the availability of design information. One
        of the primary outputs of the evaluation process is the test report as specified in the
        following requirements. <a-component id="ate_ind.1"
          name="Independent Testing – Conformance (ATE_IND.1)"> Testing is performed to confirm the
          functionality described in the <abbr linkend="TSS"/> as well as the administrative
          (including configuration and operational) documentation provided. The focus of the testing
          is to confirm that the requirements specified in <secref linkend="SFRs"/> being met,
          although some additional testing is specified for SARs in <secref linkend="SARs"/>. The
          Assurance Activities identify the additional testing activities associated with these
          components. The evaluator produces a test report documenting the plan for and results of
          testing, as well as coverage arguments focused on the platform/<abbr linkend="OS"/>
          combinations that are claiming conformance to this PP. Given the scope of the <abbr
            linkend="OS"/> and its associated evaluation evidence requirements, this component’s
          assurance activities are covered by the assurance activities listed for ALC_CMC.1.
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1d">
              <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="OS"/> for testing.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
          <group type="con-pres">
            <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1c">
              <title>The <abbr linkend="OS"/> shall be suitable for testing.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
            <a-element id="ate_ind.1.1e">
              <title>The evaluator <h:i>shall confirm</h:i> that the information provided meets all
              requirements for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
            </a-element>
            <a-element id="ate_ind.1.2e">
              <title>The evaluator shall test a subset of the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> to confirm that
              the <abbr linkend="TSF"/> operates as specified.</title>
              <note role="application">The evaluator will test the OS on the most current fully
              patched version of the platform.</note>
              <aactivity>The evaluator will prepare a test plan and report documenting the testing
              aspects of the system, including any application crashes during testing. The evaluator
              shall determine the root cause of any application crashes and include that information
              in the report. The test plan covers all of the testing actions contained in the <cite
                linkend="bibCEM"/> and the body of this PP’s Assurance Activities. <h:br/> While it is
              not necessary to have one test case per test listed in an Assurance Activity, the
              evaluator must document in the test plan that each applicable testing requirement in
              the <abbr linkend="ST"/> is covered. The test plan identifies the platforms to be
              tested, and for those platforms not included in the test plan but included in the
                <abbr linkend="ST"/>, the test plan provides a justification for not testing the
              platforms. This justification must address the differences between the tested
              platforms and the untested platforms, and make an argument that the differences do not
              affect the testing to be performed. It is not sufficient to merely assert that the
              differences have no affect; rationale must be provided. If all platforms claimed in
              the <abbr linkend="ST"/> are tested, then no rationale is necessary. The test plan
              describes the composition of each platform to be tested, and any setup that is
              necessary beyond what is contained in the AGD documentation. It should be noted that
              the evaluator is expected to follow the AGD documentation for installation and setup
              of each platform either as part of a test or as a standard pre-test condition. This
              may include special test drivers or tools. For each driver or tool, an argument (not
              just an assertion) should be provided that the driver or tool will not adversely
              affect the performance of the functionality by the <abbr linkend="OS"/> and its
              platform. <h:br/> This also includes the configuration of the cryptographic engine to be
              used. The cryptographic algorithms implemented by this engine are those specified by
              this PP and used by the cryptographic protocols being evaluated (IPsec, TLS). The test
              plan identifies high-level test objectives as well as the test procedures to be
              followed to achieve those objectives. These procedures include expected results. <h:br/>
              The test report (which could just be an annotated version of the test plan) details
              the activities that took place when the test procedures were executed, and includes
              the actual results of the tests. This shall be a cumulative account, so if there was a
              test run that resulted in a failure; a fix installed; and then a successful re-run of
              the test, the report would show a “fail” and “pass” result (and the supporting
              details), and not just the “pass” result.</aactivity>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="ava" title="Class AVA: Vulnerability Assessment">For the first generation of
        this protection profile, the evaluation lab is expected to survey open sources to discover
        what vulnerabilities have been discovered in these types of products. In most cases, these
        vulnerabilities will require sophistication beyond that of a basic attacker. Until
        penetration tools are created and uniformly distributed to the evaluation labs, the
        evaluator will not be expected to test for these vulnerabilities in the <abbr linkend="OS"
        />. The labs will be expected to comment on the likelihood of these vulnerabilities given
        the documentation provided by the vendor. This information will be used in the development
        of penetration testing tools and for the development of future protection profiles.
        <a-component id="ava_van.1" name="Vulnerability Survey (AVA_VAN.1)">
	  <group type="dev-action">
            <a-element id="ava_van.1.1d">
              <title>The developer shall provide the <abbr linkend="OS"/> for testing.</title>
            </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="con-pres">
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.1c">
            <title>The <abbr linkend="OS"/> shall be suitable for testing.</title>
          </a-element>
	  </group>
	  <group type="eval-action">
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.1e">
            <title>The evaluator shall confirm that the information provided meets all requirements
              for content and presentation of evidence.</title>
          </a-element>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.2e">
            <title>The evaluator shall perform a search of public domain sources to identify
              potential vulnerabilities in the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</title>
            <note role="application">Public domain sources include the Common Vulnerabilities 
              and Exposures (CVE) dictionary for publicly-known vulnerabilities.  Public domain
              sources also include sites which provide free checking of files for viruses.</note>
            <!-- their Usage statement does not permit us to mention VirusTotal by name without permission -->
          </a-element>
          <a-element id="ava_van.1.3e">
            <title>The evaluator shall conduct penetration testing, based on the identified
              potential vulnerabilities, to determine that the <abbr linkend="OS"/> is resistant to
              attacks performed by an attacker possessing Basic attack potential.</title>
            <aactivity>The evaluator will generate a report to document their
              findings with respect to this requirement. This report could physically be part of the
              overall test report mentioned in ATE_IND, or a separate document. The evaluator
              performs a search of public information to find vulnerabilities that have been found
              in similar applications with a particular focus on network protocols the application
              uses and document formats it parses. 
              The evaluator documents the sources consulted and
              the vulnerabilities found in the report. 
              <h:br/>
              For each vulnerability found, the evaluator
              either provides a rationale with respect to its non-applicability, or the evaluator
              formulates a test (using the guidelines provided in ATE_IND) to confirm the
              vulnerability, if suitable. Suitability is determined by assessing the attack vector
              needed to take advantage of the vulnerability. If exploiting the vulnerability
              requires expert skills and an electron microscope, for instance, then a test would not
              be suitable and an appropriate justification would be formulated.</aactivity>
          </a-element>
	  </group>
        </a-component>
      </subsection>      
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>,
    the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the <abbr linkend="OS"/>) are
    contained in the body of this PP. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements
    specified in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
      linkend="objective"/>. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included
    in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a OS to claim conformance to
    this PP. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
    in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
    appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that
    are not required in order to conform to this PP, but will be included in the baseline
    requirements in future versions of this PP, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the
    ST author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with those in
      <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref linkend="objective"/>
    but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the ST. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based"> As indicated in the introduction to
    this PP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the OS or its underlying
    platform) are contained in the body of this PP. There are additional requirements based on
    selections in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements
    below will need to be included. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This appendix includes requirements that
    specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
    mandated in the body of this PP as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available
    in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the ST such that the
    OS is still conformant to this PP, and it is expected that they be included as soon as
    possible. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Inherently Satisfied Requirements" id="satisfiedreqs"> This
	appendix lists requirements that should be considered satisfied by products
	successfully evaluated against this Protection Profile.  
	However, these requirements are not featured explicitly as SFRs and should not be
	included in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>.  
	They are not included as standalone SFRs because it would
	increase the time, cost, and complexity of evaluation.  This approach is permitted
	by <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1, <h:b>8.2 Dependencies between components</h:b>.
    <h:br/>
	This information benefits systems engineering activities which call for inclusion of 
	particular security controls.  Evaluation against the Protection Profile
	provides evidence that these controls are present and have been evaluated.
    <table>
	<tr class="header">
	<td>Requirement</td>
	<td>Rationale for Satisfaction</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FIA_UAU.1 - Timing of authentication</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FIA_AFL.1"/> implicitly requires that the OS perform all necessary actions, 
	  including those on behalf of the user who has not been authenticated, 
	  in order to authenticate;
	  therefore it is duplicative to include these actions as a 
	  separate assignment and test.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FIA_UID.1 - Timing of identification</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FIA_AFL.1"/> implicitly requires that the OS perform all necessary actions, 
	  including those on behalf of the user who has not been identified, 
	  in order to authenticate;
	  therefore it is duplicative to include these actions as a 
	  separate assignment and test.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FMT_SMR.1 - Security roles</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FMT_MOF_EXT.1"/> specifies role-based management functions that implicitly defines
	  user and privileged accounts; 
	  therefore, it is duplicative to include separate role requirements.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FPT_STM.1 - Reliable time stamps</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FAU_GEN.1.2"/> explicitly requires that the OS associate timestamps with audit records;
	  therefore it is duplicative to include a separate timestamp requirement.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FTA_SSL.1 - TSF-initiated session locking</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FMT_MOF_EXT.1"/> defines requirements for managing session locking;
	  therefore, it is duplicative to include a separate session locking requirement.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FTA_SSL.2 - User-initiated locking</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FMT_MOF_EXT.1"/> defines requirements for user-initiated session locking;
	  therefore, it is duplicative to include a separate session locking requirement.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FAU_STG.1 - Protected audit trail storage</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FPT_ACF_EXT.1"/> defines a requirement to protect audit logs;
	  therefore, it is duplicative to include a separate protection of audit trail requirements.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>FAU_GEN.2 - User identity association</td>
	<td>
	  <linkref linkend="FAU_GEN.1.2"/> explicitly requires that the OS record
	  any user account associated with each event; therefore, it is duplicative
	  to include a separate requirement to associate a user account with each
	  event.
	</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	  <td>FAU_SAR.1 - Audit review</td>
	  <td>
	    <linkref linkend="FPT_ACF_EXT.1.2"/> requires that audit logs (and other objects)
	    are protected from reading by unprivileged users; therefore, it is duplicative
	    to include a separate requirement to protect only the audit information.
	  </td>
	</tr>
    </table>

  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Entropy Documentation and Assessment" id="entropyappendix"> This appendix
    describes the required supplementary information for the entropy source used by the OS. <h:br/>
    The documentation of the entropy source should be detailed enough that, after reading, the
    evaluator will thoroughly understand the entropy source and why it can be relied upon to provide
    sufficient entropy. This documentation should include multiple detailed sections: design
    description, entropy justification, operating conditions, and health testing. This documentation
    is not required to be part of the TSS. <section id="entropydesign" title="Design Description">
      Documentation shall include the design of the entropy source as a whole, including the
      interaction of all entropy source components. Any information that can be shared regarding the
      design should also be included for any third-party entropy sources that are included in the
      product. <h:br/> The documentation will describe the operation of the entropy source to include,
      how entropy is produced, and how unprocessed (raw) data can be obtained from within the
      entropy source for testing purposes. The documentation should walk through the entropy source
      design indicating where the entropy comes from, where the entropy output is passed next, any
      post-processing of the raw outputs (hash, XOR, etc.), if/where it is stored, and finally, how
      it is output from the entropy source. Any conditions placed on the process (e.g., blocking)
      should also be described in the entropy source design. Diagrams and examples are encouraged.
      <h:br/> This design must also include a description of the content of the security boundary of
      the entropy source and a description of how the security boundary ensures that an adversary
      outside the boundary cannot affect the entropy rate. <h:br/> If implemented, the design
      description shall include a description of how third-party applications can add entropy to the
      RBG. A description of any RBG state saving between power-off and power-on shall be included. </section>
    <section id="entropyjustification" title="Entropy Justification"> There should be a technical
      argument for where the unpredictability in the source comes from and why there is confidence
      in the entropy source delivering sufficient entropy for the uses made of the RBG output (by
      this particular OS). This argument will include a description of the expected min-entropy
      rate (i.e. the minimum entropy (in bits) per bit or byte of source data) and explain that
      sufficient entropy is going into the OS randomizer seeding process. This discussion will be
      part of a justification for why the entropy source can be relied upon to produce bits with
      entropy. <h:br/> The amount of information necessary to justify the expected min-entropy rate
      depends on the type of entropy source included in the product. <h:br/> For developer provided
      entropy sources, in order to justify the min-entropy rate, it is expected that a large number
      of raw source bits will be collected, statistical tests will be performed, and the min-entropy
      rate determined from the statistical tests. While no particular statistical tests are required
      at this time, it is expected that some testing is necessary in order to determine the amount
      of min-entropy in each output. <h:br/> For third-party provided entropy sources, in which the
      OS vendor has limited access to the design and raw entropy data of the source, the
      documentation will indicate an estimate of the amount of min-entropy obtained from this
      third-party source. It is acceptable for the vendor to “assume” an amount of min-entropy,
      however, this assumption must be clearly stated in the documentation provided. In particular,
      the min-entropy estimate must be specified and the assumption included in the ST. <h:br/>
      Regardless of type of entropy source, the justification will also include how the DRBG is
      initialized with the entropy stated in the ST, for example by verifying that the min-entropy
      rate is multiplied by the amount of source data used to seed the DRBG or that the rate of
      entropy expected based on the amount of source data is explicitly stated and compared to the
      statistical rate. If the amount of source data used to seed the DRBG is not clear or the
      calculated rate is not explicitly related to the seed, the documentation will not be
      considered complete. <h:br/> The entropy justification shall not include any data added from any
      third-party application or from any state saving between restarts. </section>
    <section id="entropyoperatingconditions" title="Operating Conditions"> The entropy rate may be
      affected by conditions outside the control of the entropy source itself. For example, voltage,
      frequency, temperature, and elapsed time after power-on are just a few of the factors that may
      affect the operation of the entropy source. As such, documentation will also include the range
      of operating conditions under which the entropy source is expected to generate random data. It
      will clearly describe the measures that have been taken in the system design to ensure the
      entropy source continues to operate under those conditions. Similarly, documentation shall
      describe the conditions under which the entropy source is known to malfunction or become
      inconsistent. Methods used to detect failure or degradation of the source shall be included. </section>
    <section id="entropyhealthtesting" title="Health Testing"> More specifically, all entropy source
      health tests and their rationale will be documented. This includes a description of the health
      tests, the rate and conditions under which each health test is performed (e.g., at start,
      continuously, or on-demand), the expected results for each health test, and rationale
      indicating why each test is believed to be appropriate for detecting one or more failures in
      the entropy source. </section>
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="References" id="biblio">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <h:ul>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
          </h:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R4.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation Methodology</h:a>,
          CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September 2012. </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCESG">
        <tag>CESG</tag>
        <description>CESG - <h:a
            href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/end-user-devices-security-guidance"> End
            User Devices Security and Configuration Guidance</h:a></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCSA">
        <tag>CSA</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/SMA/ispab/documents/csa_87.txt">Computer Security Act
            of 1987</h:a>, H.R. 145, June 11, 1987. </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibOMB">
        <tag>OMB</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/memoranda/fy2006/m06-19.pdf"
            >Reporting Incidents Involving Personally Identifiable Information and Incorporating the
            Cost for Security in Agency Information Technology Investments</h:a>, OMB M-06-19, July
          12, 2006. </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ANSI</term>
        <description>American National Standards Institute</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>API</term>
        <description>Application Programming Interface</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ASLR</term>
        <description>Address Space Layout Randomization</description>
      </entry>
      <!-- Never used -->
      <!-- <entry> -->
      <!--   <term>CDSA</term> -->
      <!--   <description>Common Data Security Architecture</description> -->
      <!-- </entry> -->
      <entry>
        <term>CESG</term>
        <description>Communications-Electronics Security Group</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CMC</term>
        <description>Certificate Management over CMS</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CMS</term>
        <description>Cryptographic Message Syntax</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CN</term>
        <description>Common Names</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CRL</term>
        <description>Certificate Revocation List</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CSA</term>
        <description>Computer Security Act</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DEP</term>
        <description>Data Execution Prevention</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DES</term>
        <description>Data Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DHE</term>
        <description>Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DNS</term>
        <description>Domain Name System</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DRBG</term>
        <description>Deterministic Random Bit Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DSS</term>
        <description>Digital Signature Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DT</term>
        <description>Date/Time Vector</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DTLS</term>
        <description>Datagram Transport Layer Security</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>EAP</term>
        <description>Extensible Authentication Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECDHE</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman Ephemeral</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECDSA</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>EST</term>
        <description>Enrollment over Secure Transport</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FIPS</term>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DSS</term>
        <description>Digital Signature Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>HMAC</term>
        <description>Hash-based Message Authentication Code</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>HTTP</term>
        <description>Hypertext Transfer Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>HTTPS</term>
        <description>Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DSS</term>
        <description>Digital Signature Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <!-- <entry> -->
      <!--   <term>IEC</term> -->
      <!--   <description>International Electrotechnical Commission</description> -->
      <!-- </entry> -->
      <entry>
        <term>IETF</term>
        <description>Internet Engineering Task Force</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IP</term>
        <description>Internet Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ISO</term>
        <description>International Organization for Standardization</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IT</term>
        <description>Information Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ITSEF</term>
        <description>Information Technology Security Evaluation Facility</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NFC</term>
        <description>Near Field Communication</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIAP</term>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>NIST</term>
        <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OCSP</term>
        <description>Online Certificate Status Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OID</term>
        <description>Object Identifier</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OMB</term>
        <description>Office of Management and Budget</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>OS</term>
        <description>Operating System</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PII</term>
        <description>Personally Identifiable Information</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PKI</term>
        <description>Public Key Infrastructure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PP</term>
        <description>Protection Profile</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RBG</term>
        <description>Random Bit Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RFC</term>
        <description>Request for Comment</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RNG</term>
        <description>Random Number Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RNGVS</term>
        <description>Random Number Generator Validation System</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SAN</term>
        <description>Subject Alternative Name</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SAR</term>
        <description>Security Assurance Requirement</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SFR</term>
        <description>Security Functional Requirement</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SHA</term>
        <description>Secure Hash Algorithm</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>S/MIME</term>
        <description>Secure/Multi-purpose Internet Mail Extensions</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SIP</term>
        <description>Session Initiation Protocol</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SWID</term>
        <description>Software Identification</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TLS</term>
        <description>Transport Layer Security</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>URI</term>
        <description>Uniform Resource Identifier</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>URL</term>
        <description>Uniform Resource Locator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>USB</term>
        <description>Universal Serial Bus</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>XCCDF</term>
        <description>eXtensible Configuration Checklist Description Format</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>XOR</term>
        <description>Exclusive Or</description>
      </entry>
    </acronyms>
  </appendix>
</PP>
